Lawrence F. Morico Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Lawrence F. Morico Papers.
circa 1955-1958
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Morico, Lawrence F.
1 linear foot
Lawrence Morico was born 2 April 1936 and completed his undergraduate education at the University of Connecticut in 1958.
MSS19970076
Biography
Lawrence Morico was born 2 April 1936 and completed his undergraduate education at the University of Connecticut in 1958. He went on to receive degrees from the University of Bridgeport (M.S., 1961), Southern Connecticut State University (M.S., 1970; 1974). While at UConn, Morico was involved served on the Senior Class executive board and participated on the track team his freshman year. Morico taught history and social studies at Brothers of Holy Cross (1959-1961), Ridgefield High School (1961-1964) and North Branford High School (1964-1966). In June of 1998 he retired as Guidance Counselor at Wilbur Cross High School in New Haven, CT, after thirty-two years. Morico and his wife, Leatrice, have three sons and live in New Haven, CT.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of notes on lectures, syllabi, examinations and textbooks relating to Mr. Morico's education at the University of Connecticut. Mr. Morico graduated in 1958. Citations to the textbooks removed from the collection are included in this finding aid.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Alumae--Personal papers.
Subjects:
Education--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Notebooks.; Publications.
Occupations:
Educator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Mr. Morico in January 1997.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, circa 1955-1958
  - Class notes
    - French 161 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - French 162 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - French 163 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - French 164 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Math 108 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Government 216 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Psychology 268 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Geology 103 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Astronomy 155 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Art 135 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Philosophy 100 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - History 232 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - History 222 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - History 224 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - History 231 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - History 285 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Government 241 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Plant Science 129 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - English 105 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Migrant Program (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Government 252 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - History 225 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - History 256 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Business 271 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Psychology 131 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Government 201 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - French 161 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Art 241 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - History 255 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Government 254 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - Economics 111 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - History 219 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Education 402 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - Social Education 380-B (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - Education 451 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Education 414 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Education 401 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Education 452 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - Government 131 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - Government 132 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
    - Exams (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    - History 110-112 (Box 1:, Folder 42)
  - Textbooks:
    - Baldwin, Robert C.; James McPeek. An Introduction to Philosophy Through Literature. New York: The Ronald Press Company, 1950.
    - Barton, Francis B. and Edward H. Sirich. Practical French Review Grammar and Composition. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1954.
    - Cantarella, Michele and Paul L. Richards. Dieci Novelle Contemporance. New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1938.
    - Clyde, Paul Hibbert. The Far East: A History of the Impact of the West on Eastern Asia. Second edition. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1953.
    - Emmons, William H., George A. Thiel, Clinton R. Stauffer and Ira S. Allison. Geology Principles and Processes. Fourth edition. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1955.
    - Fath, Edward Arthur. The Elements of Astronomy. New York: McGraw -Hill Book Company, Inc., 1955.
    - Foster, Michael B. Masters of Political Thought: Plato to Machiavelli. Cambridge, MA: The Riverside Press, 1941.
    - Galpin, Alfred M. and E.E. Milligan. Intermediate Readings in French Prose. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1957.
    - Gavit, Bernard C. Introduction to the Study of Law. Brooklyn, NY: The Foundation Press, Inc., 1951.
    - Hall, Walter Phelps; William Stearns Davis. The Course of Europe since Waterloo. Third edition. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1957.
    - Hicks, John D. A Short History of American Democracy. Boston: Houghton-Mifflin, 1949.
    - Hinderaker, Ivan. Party Politics. New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1956.
    - Homan, Paul T., Albert Gailord Hart and Arnold W. Sametz. The Economic Order: An Introduction to Theory and Policy and Student Guide to The Economic Order. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1958.
    - Knappen, Marshall. An Introduction to American Foreign Policy. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1956.
    - Lucke, John B. and Janet M. Aitken. Physical Geology Laboratory Manual. New York: Ronald Press, 1953.
    - Mason, Alpheus Thomas and William M. Beaney. American Constitutional Law. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1954.
    - Moss, H. St. L. B. the Birth of the Middle Ages, 395-814. London: Oxford University Press, 1935.
    - Northen, Henry T. Introductory Plant Science. New York: Ronald Press, 1953.
    - Pinson, Koppel S. Modern Germany: Its History and Civilization. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1954.
    - Robb, David M. and J.J. Garrison. Art in the Western World. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1953.
    - Schleicher, Charles P. Introduction to International Relations. New York: Prentice-Hall, 1954.
    - Starr, Wilmarth H., Alfred G. Pellegrino and Henri A. Casavant. Functional French. New York: American Book Company, 1951.
    - Thompson, Craig P. and John Hicks. Thought and Experience in Prose. New York: Oxford University Press, 1954.
    - von Rauch, Georg. A History of Soviet Russia. Revised edition. New York: Frederick A. Praeger, 1958.
    - Wallbank, T. Walter and Alastair H. Taylor. Civilization Past and Present. N.P.: Scott, Foresman and Company, 1954.